ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
なんば　ひ　び　と
(南波日々人)前からさ 一度で➡
There's something I've always wanted to try.
いいから やって
みたかったんだよな｡
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
月面を ひとりで散歩｡
Taking a walk on the moon by myself.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)ヒビト…ヒビト！
Hibito... Hibito...
Eight minutes of oxygen left...
《酸素残量…８分｡➡
８分か クソッ！》
Eight minutes, huh?
Damn!
《どうせ死ぬなら また
あの谷に落っこちて…｡➡
If I have to die, I'd rather go back in the ravine
満天の星でも見ながらが いいな》
and look up at the stars.
《そうするか》
Might as well.
あ…あれは？
Th-That's...
Space Brothers
I can no longer remember
what I tried to forget
When I peeked through the telescope
I realized that our world is tiny
It was a picture of infinity
It's not a one-time thing
We'll walk together
Once we've passed the clouds,
we will hold the world between our fingers
and keep what we lost in mind
#43 Brian
せい
オリオン ドッキング準備完了｡➡
Orion ready to dock.
全システム異常なし｡
順調に移動中｡➡
All systems reading normal.
Moving smoothly.
Panel confirmed as green.
パネル グリーンを確認｡
前方クリア｡➡
Your path is clear.
機体水平｡速度安定｡➡
Trajectory and speed are stable.
３･２･１ スタート｡
Three, two, one, start.
Fourteen meters to target.
目標まで１４メートル｡
Nine meters.
９メートル｡
Twelve meters?
１２メートル…あれ？
離れていく｡
Er, I'm moving away...
ダメだ｡コントロールが
効かない｡ヒューストン！
It won't work. The controls aren't responding.
Houston!
手順を間違えてないか？
Did you make a mistake in the procedure?
No, that can't be it.
いや そんなはずはない｡
何度も確認してる｡
I've double checked every step.
１５分あけて もう一度やろう｡
We'll take a fifteen-minute break before trying again.
りょうかい
了解｡
Roger that.
全システム異常なし｡
パネル グリーンを確認｡➡
All systems reading normal.
Panel confirmed as green.
前方クリア｡機体水平｡速度安定｡➡
Your path is clear.
Trajectory and speed are stable.
３･２･１ スタート｡
Three, two, one, start.
Fourteen meters to target.
目標まで１６メートル｡
９メートル｡
Nine meters.
There we go again...
まただ…どんどん離れていく｡
おかしいなぁ｡
It's getting away from me.
That's weird...
けい
いったん 休憩しよう｡
プログラムをチェックする｡
Take a breather.
We'll check the program.
了解｡
Roger that.
ハァ｡
おやじ
《親父のような…
兄貴のような…➡
He was like a father, like an older brother.
せんぱい
あるいは友人のような大先輩》
Like a friend who'd been through it all.
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)来てやったぞ ヒビト｡
I'm here, Hibito.
大先輩 ブライアン･Ｊが
わざわざ来てやったぞ｡
The veteran Brian Jay came all the way to see you...
《別に…来てとか
たの
頼んでね～のに》
I didn't ask you to come here.
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)助けてやるよ ヒビト｡
どこが わかんね～んだ？
I'll give you some help, Hibito.
What are you having trouble with?
いいよ 自分でやるから｡
It's okay. I'll figure it out myself.
なんだよ 助けさせろよ｡
What? Let me help you.
I want to show everyone how super I am.
みんなに俺がどんなに
優秀なのかを見せたいんだよ｡
んな事 もうみんな知ってるよ｡
Everyone knows how super you are.
ホラ！どけ！
《めんどくせ～！》
Come on, move.
He's such a pain...
ちょっと持っててくれ｡
(ｽﾀｯﾌ)あっはい｡
Hold this for me.
Oh, sure!
Let's take a look...
《自分大好き人間だな…この人》
This guy really loves himself.
え？ここ？ここが
わかんないの？ヒビト君!?
Wait, this is it?
You can't figure this out, Hibito?
よぉ～し 俺にまかせろ！お前は
ホントにラッキーボーイだ｡
Okay, let me handle this.
You're such a lucky boy.
《ふざけたおじさんだな｡➡
He was just a joker.
最初は そう思った｡いや
実際 そうなんだけど》
That was my initial impression.
Well, I wasn't too far off.
もう６回も同じとこで
ミスってんだよ｡
I've made the same mistake, in the same place, six times in a row.
操作ミスのはず
ね～んだけどさ｡
It can't be an operational error.
ああ～わかった｡
I see now.
この図面 昔のだぞ｡
This is an old diagram.
Huh?
日付 見りゃ わかんだろ｡
間違って古いの渡されたんだな｡➡
Just look at the date.
They must have given you an outdated one by mistake.
ほら セクション７６のとこが
違うぞ｡
See? Section 67 has changed.
《全然 気付かなかった》
I completely missed that...
スイッチの配置とか
ところどころ変わってるからな｡➡
They've changed the switch positions since then.
そりゃ誤作動するわ｡
No wonder you're having trouble.
はい こちらブライアン｡
ああ 今 オリオンだよ｡
Yeah, this is Brian.
Yeah, I'm inside Orion right now.
違うよ シミュレーターの方｡
No, the Orion simulator.
ああ そうだな
次の地質調査ミッションには➡
Yeah, that's right.
There's a bowling task as part of the next survey mission, right?
ボーリングタスクがあるだろ？
ニックがいいぞ｡
You should try Nick.
He's a pro at module docking.
そうさ
モジュール固定実験の操作も
天才的にうまかった｡
あれならボーリングタスクも
難なく こなせるはずだ｡
The bowling task should be easy for him.
《他の誰かに
別件の説明をしながら➡
He uses a finger to direct me,
俺には指で
ばん
基盤の説明をしてくる》
while explaining something totally different to someone else.
《ホントに器用だな
こんな芸当ができる人間は…》
He's got a sharp mind...
I can only think of one other person
《あと１人くらいしか
知らない》
who can multitask like this.
まったく…こんな初歩的な間違い
２秒で気付けよ｡ヒビト｡➡
Honestly...
It should take you two seconds to notice a newbie mistake like this, Hibito.
ひか
そんなんで よく俺の控えに
なれたもんだ！
How were you chosen to be my backup?
すいせん
《あんたが推薦したんだろ｡
俺みたいな新人を》
Weren't you the one who chose a newbie?
もう二度と来てやらね～からな｡
自分で何とかしろ｡
I won't come back again.
Figure out what to do on your own.
《あれ…まただ》
Oh? Again?
《また昨日と同じ展開》
That's what he said yesterday.
《こんな感じで明日も
来るんだろうな｡➡
He'll probably be back tomorrow, then.
And he'll demonstrate his superiority.
そして また…格の差を
見せ付けられる》
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)フフン｡
I'm here, Hibito.
来てやったぞ ヒビト｡
大先輩 ブライアン･Ｊが｡
The veteran Brian Jay...
現在
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝの声)来てやったぞ｡
...came to see you.
ハァハァ…ブライ…アン｡
Brian...
ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
ハァ…ハァ…｡
良かった…ハァ…｡
Oh, good.
ちゃんとある｡
It's real.
うす
げんかく
酸素が薄くなって幻覚を
見てんのかと思った｡
I thought it might be a hallucination, induced by low oxygen.
ハァ…｡
そうか…｡
I see...
《ブライアンがこれを…ここに➡
Brian put this here...
兄弟で月面に立つ事を願って…》
Because he hoped both brothers would stand on the moon together.
《悪いな…ムッちゃん…》
Sorry,
Mu...
ほしか
(管制官)星加さん…➡
Hoshika...
日々人君の酸素残量が
あと３分です｡
Hibito's down to three minutes of oxygen.
むった
(原田)酸素のこと 六太さんに
知らせなくても？
Shouldn't we tell Mutta?
通話が出来るなら ともかく…➡
Perhaps if there were a way to communicate.
But I don't want him to have to stare at a monitor while his brother
ただモニターの酸素数値が
減っていくのを…見せたくない｡
runs out of oxygen.
《ピッタリだったのに…➡
But he guessed right...
六太さんが示したポイントと
ヒビトさんの信号が出た地点が➡
Hibito's signal came from the exact location Mutta indicated!
全く同じだったのに…！》
If Houston had listened to our request...
ようせい
《ヒューストンがこちらの要請に
こた
応えてくれていれば…！》
へへ…そりゃそうだよな…｡
Naturally...
《ブライアンは たしかに…》
Proof that Brian...
...really did once stand here.
《ここに立っていたんだ！》
(管制官)あと…１分です…｡
There's one minute left...
Guess this is it...
そろそろか…｡
エコー
Here I am, Hibito.
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝの声)来てやったぞ ヒビト｡
助けてやろうか？
大先輩 ブライアン･Ｊが｡
Want the veteran Brian Jay to help you out?
へへ…全くだ｡
Yeah...
今こそ…助けてほしいね…｡
This is one time I could use your help.
《悪い…ムッちゃん》
Sorry, Mu...
Damn it!
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ)クソォ！ヒビトの酸素が
なくなっちまう！
Hibito's gonna run out of oxygen!
Stay calm, Buddy...
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)落ち着け バディ！
俺達まで事故に遭うぞ！
Or else we'll also get in an accident!
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ)えいっ わかってるが
ヒビト達のとこまで➡
I know that.
But we're still twelve kilometers away!
まだ１２キロもある！
ヒビトが…ヒビトが死んじまう！
Hibito's gonna...
Hibito's gonna die!
えいっ ぐおおおお！
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)聞け バディ！俺達は今！
Listen to me, Buddy!
We're doing the best we can!
さいぜん
最善を尽くしている！
これ以上はないんだ！
わかってるだろ！
There's nothing else we can do...
You know that, right?
Focus on reaching our destination safely!
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)ただ目的地に無事に
たどり着く事だけ考えろ！
エコー
《時間だ…》
It's time...
This is Houston!
あずま
(吾妻)こちら ヒューストン！
日々人 応答してくれ！➡
Hibito, do you read me?
こちら ヒューストン 吾妻だ！
応答しろ！日々人！
This is Houston!
It's Azuma!
Come in, Hibito!
Azuma...
(管制官)《アズマ…》
こちら ヒューストン！
This is Houston!
Hibito's oxygen system is about to stop.
ヒビトの酸素供給が止まります！
あと１０秒！➡
Ten seconds.
９…８…｡
(ｸﾗｳﾄﾞ)やめろ！
Nine...
Eight...
Stop.
(ｸﾗｳﾄﾞ)秒読みなどするな｡
Don't count down the seconds.
Hibito!
日々人！
《ヒビト…》
Hibito...
(南波六太)♪～(鼻歌)
《日々人…お前は…》
Hibito...
You'll
come back, like nothing went wrong at all.
《また…な～んもなかった
みたいに戻ってこいよ》
Oxygen supply exhausted.
酸素供給停止！宇宙服内の
空気中酸素は２０％から下降中！
Oxygen within spacesuit falling under twenty percent!
ハァハァ…頭が…ぐぅ！
My head!
うぅ！ぐああ…！
ハァハァ…ハッハッ！
《くそ‼死ぬのか…！》
Damn!
Am I gonna die?
《体が…熱い！》
My body is burning up...
ああ…ああ…ハァハァ…｡
助けてやろうか？ヒビト｡
Want me to help you, Hibito?
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝの声)オーッス ヒビト！
Yo, Hibito!
《ブライアン…！》
Brian...
来てやったぞ ヒビト｡➡
Here I am, Hibito.
この大先輩 ブライアン･Ｊが➡
The veteran Brian Jay
来てやったぞ｡
is here to save the day.
We have visual!
ブライアン
映ったぞ！ＢＲＩＡＮのカメラに
ヒビトが映った！
We have Hibito on Brian's camera!
Is Hibito okay?
(ｸﾗｳﾄﾞ)ヒビトは無事か!?
わかりません｡倒れてます｡
I can't tell! He's on the ground!
He's moving!
動いた！立とうとしてるんだ！
He's trying to stand!
Hibito!
(管制官)ヒビト！
Yes, Hibito!
そうだ日々人！立て！
ＢＲＩＡＮから酸素を受け取れ！
Stand up!
Take oxygen from Brian!
Hibito!
(吾妻)日々人～‼
ハァッ！ハァ！ハァ！
ハァ！ハァ！ハァ！
ハハッ ハァ…ブライアン…｡
Brian...
やっぱり…来てくれるんだな｡
あんたは…｡
You really did come for me...
The stones out in the fields
are worn down by their daily existence and disappear
That's their trial
When will we be able to resist fate?
Before you lose all hope
and say that we can't win against gravity
go without stopping
past the goal line
You have such strong convictions
Leave your footprints on this Earth
Maybe their tiny length will cause a miracle in the end
Give us a magnificent jump
Run now and do it
Jump past all you see overhead
This is your stride
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#44 Three Astronauts
＜月面の日々人は
なんとか助かった＞
Hibito survived his lunar accident somehow.
I didn't even know he was losing oxygen.
＜まさか 酸素まで
なくなってたなんてな＞
Afterward, I got to talk to Hibito.
＜そんな中 私は
日々人と会話することに＞
＜どうだよ？そっちの暮らしは｡➡
"So how's life up there?"
"Anything dangerous happen?"
何か危険な目に
遭ったりしてねえか？➡
And his response was it's all peace and quiet here.
…って聞いたら ｢フン そうだな｡
いたって平和だ｣だって＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Three Astronauts"
Hibito, who were the three astronauts that saved you?
＜日々人 お前を助けた
３人の宇宙飛行士って 誰だ？＞
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
This week's space photo!
There's gravity!
今週の宇宙写真です！
すっげぇ！
Awesome!